A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20 FA292
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
1918-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harkness, Edward Stephen
Harkness, Charles W.
Harkness, Mary Emma Stillman
Harkness, Anna M. Richardson
Commonwealth Fund
FA292
111.76 Cubic Feet 254 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Conditions Governing Access note
Processing of the individual fellowship files (Subseries 2) has been completed, and they are open to researchers. Although the administrative files (Subseries 1) will be processed at a later date, they can be made available for research when the Center is given advance notice of a researcher's interest.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Rockefeller Archive Center acquired a major portion of the Commonwealth Fund archives in 1986. This initial deposit included fifty-five cubic feet of administrative records and fellowship files from the Fund's Harkness Fellowship offices in New York and London. Subsequent transfers of records, primarily fellowship files, added another seventy cubic feet of documents.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
Biographical/Historical note
The Harkness Fellowship program followed the philanthropic aims of Edward S. Harkness, his mother Anna M. Harkness, and his wife Mary. When the Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 in New York, its mandate was simply "to do something for the welfare of mankind." Edward Harkness' fondness for the British people and his desire to promote closer relationships between the U.S. and Great Britain stemmed from his personal love of England's traditions, particularly the treasures of the independent colleges at Oxford and Cambridge. The fellowship program began in 1925 with twenty fellowships for British graduate students to study in the United States. According to the Fund's annual report for that year, the program stemmed from the trustees' belief that "International understanding can be provided in no more practicable way than through the provision of International opportunities for education and travel to young men and women of outstanding character and ability." By helping potential British leaders become "familiar... with the institutions, customs, and ways of thinking" in the U.S., the program would create "a force for mutual understanding and good feeling" which would in turn promote "unity of thought and purpose on the part of the two great English speaking nations of the world."
Over the years, a number of changes in the original guidelines of the program broadened the scope of the fellowships. In 1929, the program also provided civil service fellowships to British subjects holding posts in various overseas departments of the British government. This broadened eligibility to include candidates from government service in Australia and New Zealand.
Eligibility was expanded again in 1959 to include non-civil servants in New Zealand and Australia, and eventually in 1960, applicants from Italy, France, Holland, Germany, Switzerland, and Norway were also considered.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents note
The records of the Harkness Fellowships reflect the close personal relationship the Fund Instituted with over 1,800 fellows. A typical file in Series 20.2 contains a fellow's application, his curriculum vitae and letters of recommendation, his fellowship report, and photographs. It was not unusual for fellows and officials at the Commonwealth Fund to maintain correspondence for more than twenty years, and files often contain family photographs, professional writings, and newspaper clippings from fellows who succeeded in a wide variety of fields. Such files clearly demonstrate that close and personal relationships were maintained by the Fund and the Harkness fellows.
The program guidelines required that every fellow spend a significant portion of the fellowship in travel, an "obligation" highly prized by the fellows. Their travel experiences were an important educational factor and lasting benefit, and were often praised in the reports the fellows were required to submit after their return home.
These fellowship reports, written from the viewpoint of a foreigner, provide tremendous insight into American culture. Indeed, one Harkness fellow based a career on such insights. "It changed my life," Alistair Cooke wrote of his fellowship in literature shortly after completing it in 1932. Cooke's fellowship file consists of reports and correspondence (1932-1989) that document his stay in the U.S. and his eventual rise to fame with the British Broadcasting Company.
War relief; United States; Public welfare; Public health; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Child mental health; Child psychology; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Medicine, Rural; Mental health; Education, Rural; Child welfare; Law; Hygiene; Legal research; Legal issues; Medical research; Medical education; Harkness, Edward Stephen; Columbia University; Harvard University; Phillips Exeter Academy; Harkness, Charles W.; Harkness, Mary Emma Stillman; Social Science Research Council; Harkness, Anna M. Richardson; Yale University; Commonwealth Fund
- Administrative Files, 1
- Fellowship Files, 1920-1993; 2; 242 Box(es)
  Arrangement note
  Subseries 2 is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the fellow.
  - Abraham, Michael Frederick Hayne - 1955 - England - Forestry, 1954-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abravanel, Daniela - 1977 - Italy - Psychology, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted - Confidential material.
  - Abravanel, Daniela - 1977 - Italy - Psychology, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ackroyd, Dorothy Elizabeth - 1949 - England - Natural Resources, 1949-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Acock, Adrian Martin - 1938 - England - Botany, 1938-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Acton, Peter Hampden - 1978 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Christopher John - 1971 - England - Chemistry, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adams, Christopher John - 1971 - England - Chemistry, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adams, John Brett - 1962 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adams, John Frank - 1957 - England - Mathematics, 1957-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adams, John William Lane - 1933 - England - Economics, 1933-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Adams, Michael Evelyn - 1954 - England - Mass Media, 1953-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Adams, Robert Whitehouse - 1930 - England - Engineering, 1930-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Adamson, Alastair Martin - 1926 - England - Zoology, 1926-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Alexander, Henry Gavin - 1956 - England - Philosophy and Logic, 1955-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Alexander, Michael O'Donel Bjarne - 1960 - England - History, 1959-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Alexander, Spyro Marcus St. John - 1983 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Alexandre, Bernard - 1960 - France - Business and Industrials Studies, 1959-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Alkema, Auke Theodore - 1955 - Netherlands - Economics, 1955-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Allan, George William Crawford - 1932 - England - Engineering, Metallurgy and Applied Sciences, 1932-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Allen, Arthur Charles - 1951 - England - Mathematics, 1950-1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Allen, George Cameron - 1934 - Germany - Literature and Drama, 1934-1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Allen, George Cameron - 1934 - Germany - Literature and Drama, 1934-1990 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Allen, Harry Cranbrook - 1946 - England - American Studies, 1939-1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Allen, Harry Cranbrook - 1946 - England - American Studies, 1939-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Allen, Paul Howard - 1979 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Allen, Phillip - 1948 - England - Political Science, Public Administration, and International Relations, 1948-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Allison, Lincoln - 1975 - England - Political Science, Public Administration, and International Relations, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Alman, John Harold - 1955 - England - Education, 1954-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Alston, James Maxwell - 1927 - England - Biochemistry, 1927-1979 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Amendola, Mario - 1967 - Italy - Economics, 1965-1981 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Andersen, Astrid Hjertenses - 1952 - Netherlands - Literature and Drama, 1951-1987 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Anderson, Hilary Jean - 1978 - England - Zoology, 1977-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Anderson, John Edgar - 1966 - England - Chemistry, 1965-1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Anderson, Patrick John McAlister - 1938 - England - English, 1938-1980 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Andler, Daniel - 1969 - France - Mathematics and Statistics, 1968-1985 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Andrew, Edward Raymond - 1948 - England - Physics, 1948-1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Andrews, Glyn Llewellyn - 1966 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1965-1980 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Andrews, John Michael Geoffrey - 1956 - England - Business and Industrial Studies, 1936-1986 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Related Archival Materials note
    Photographs
  - Andrews, Samuel - 1925 - England - Biochemistry, 1925-1982 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Angear, Thomas Richard - 1961 - England - Business, 1960-1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Angus, Robert Henry - 1928 - England - Engineering, 1928-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Appels, Rudolf - 1979 - Australia - Chemistry, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Arbuz, Georges - 1962 - France - Sociology, 1961-1975 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Armitage, Arthur Llewellyn - 1937 - England - Law, 1936-1984 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Armitage, David Richard - 1988 - England - English Literature, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Armstrong, William Arthur - 1940 - England - Literature, 1940-1986 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Arnold, Ronald Nathan - 1934 - England - Engineering, 1934-1960 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Ashby, Eric - 1929 - England - Biological Sciences, 1929-1989 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Asher, Raynor John - 1973 - New Zealand - Law, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Ashley, John - 1954 - England - Politics and Television, 1954-1990 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Ashworth, John Michael - 1965 - England - Biochemistry, 1964-1987 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Asquith, John Dixon - 1987 - England - Manufacturing Engineering, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Asselbergs, Gustave - 1966 - Netherlands - Mass Media, 1956-1968 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Astbury, Frank Nicholas - 1926 - England - Architecture, 1926-1980 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Atiyah, Michael Francis - 1955 - England - Mathematics, 1954-1984 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Atkins, Peter William - 1964 - England - Chemistry, 1963-1978 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Atkinson, Joseph Bryan - 1971 - New Zealand - Political Science, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Atteslander, Peter Max - 1952 - Switzerland - Industrial Sociology, 1952-1982 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Austin, Peter Kenneth - 1978 - Australia - Linguistics, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Aylward, Francis Xavier - 1935 - England - Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, 1935-1979 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Bacon, Christopher John - 1959 - England - Political Science, 1958-1990 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Baddeley, Margaret Susan - 1965 - England - Botany, 1964-1984 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Baier, Kirsten - 1968 - Germany - Political Science, Public Administration, and International Relations, 1967-1986 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Bailey, Alan Marshall - 1963 - England - Public Administration, 1962-1982 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Bailey, Allen Jackson - 1963 - England - Biological Sciences, 1963-1984 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Baily, Harold John - 1964 - Australia - Painting and Sculpture, 1963-1985 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Baker, Neil Reeves - 1974 - England - Biomedical Sciences, 1973-1988 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Balder, Erik Jan - 1973 - Netherlands - Mathematics and Statistics, 1972-1980 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Baldwin, Rodney Gordon - 1971 - New Zealand - Political Science, Public Administration, and International Relations, 1971-1980 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Ball, John Nicholas - 1961 - England - Biological Sciences, 1961-1990 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Ballabeni, Roberto - 1969 - Italy - Sociology, 1969-1974 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Band, Stephen Henry - 1981 - England - Business Administration, 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Bannard, Edward Yorke - 1956 - England - Public Administration, 1956-1986 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Barak, Montefiore - 1929 - New Zealand - Physical Chemistry, 1929-1970 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Barbour, Robert Alexander Stewart - 1952 - England - Theology, 1951-1982 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Barclay, William Arthur - 1964 - Australia - Community Psychiatry, 1961-1985 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Barie, Ottavio - 1959 - Italy - History, 1956-1980 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Barker, Simon Ross - 1978 - England - Mathematics, 1977-1988 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Barker, William Alan - 1951 - England - History, 1951-1962 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Barnes, Denis Charles - 1952 - England - Sociology, 1951-1979 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Barnett, Stephen Frank - 1951 - England - Biology, 1951-1955 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Barnicoat, Cuthbert Richmond - 1936 - New Zealand - Scientific and Industrial Research, 1936-1980 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Barrett, Timothy Hugh - 1971 - England - Religious Studies, 1970-1987 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Barrett, Wilfred Phillips - 1928 - England - Literature, 1928-1978 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Barringer, Timothy John - 1988 - England - Art History, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Bartlam, Edward Reginald - 1936 - England - Education, 1936-1947 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Bartlett, Geoffrey Ray - 1983 - Australia - Sculpture, 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Bartlett, Henry Francis - 1938 - England - History, 1937-1990 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Barton, Nicholas James - 1967 - England - Medicine and Biomedical Science, 1960-1989 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Baskerville, Stephen William - 1976 - England - History, 1975-1985 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Basso, Carlo - 1966 - Italy - History, 1964-1986 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Bataille, Michele - 1970 - France - Computers and Operational Research, 1970-1987 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Bate, Andrew Jonathan - 1980 - England - English Literature, 1979-1988 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Bateman, John Burraston - 1937 - England - Biophysics, 1935-1981 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Bates, David - 1974 - England - Medicine and Biomedical Science, 1973-1989 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Bates, Stewart - 1934 - England - Economics, 1934-1965 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Bateson, Frederick Noel Wilse - 1927 - England - English Literature, 1927-1979 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Bateson, Paul Patrick Gordon Berg - 1963 - England - Psychology, 1963-1987 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Bathurst, James Charles - 1977 - England - Environmental Science, 1976-1985 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Battersby, Alan Rushton - 1950 - England - Organic Chemistry, 1950-1984 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Baumfield, David Leslie - 1964 - New Zealand - Journalism, 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Baumgart, Ian Lawrence - 1962 - New Zealand - Administration, 1962-1987 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Baxter, William Threipland - 1931 - England - Economics and Business History, 1931-1985 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Bayliss, Noel Stanley - 1930 - England - Chemistry, 1930-1975 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Beadle, Noel Charles William - 1948 - Australia - Ecology, 1942-1975 (Box 13, Folder 106)
  - Beaglehole, Ernest - 1931 - England - Chemistry, 1930-1962 (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - Beaglehole, Timothy Holmes - 1966 - New Zealand - East Asian History, 1963-1984 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Beale, Roger David Bernard - 1973 - Australia - Economics, 1972-1985 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - Bean, Charles Richard - 1979 - England - Economics, 1978-1987 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - Beardmore, John Alec - 1956 - England - Genetics, 1955-1988 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Beare, Hedley - 1967 - Australia - Educational Administration, 1966-1981 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Beauman, Christopher Burgoyne Bentley - 1966 - England - International Relations and Economics, 1965-1990 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Beaumont, Peter - 1969 - England - Geography and Statistics, 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - Beck, Thomas George Gordon - 1931 - New Zealand - Engineering, 1931-1948 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Beecroft, Paul Adrian Barlow - 1974 - England - Business Administration, 1974-1989 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Beedham, Brian James - 1956 - England - Politics, 1954-1989 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Bell, Christine - 1989 - England - Law, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Bellamy, Albert Alexander - 1956 - England - Architecture, 1956-1981 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Bellamy, Albert Alexander - 1956 - England - Architecture, 1956-1981 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Bellamy, Albert Alexander - 1956 - England - Architecture, 1956-1981 (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - Bellerby, John Rotherford - 1925 - England - Economics, 1920-1977 (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - Bellis, Leslie Victor - 1959 - England - Economics, 1958-1977 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - Belt, Katheryn Tertia - 1985 - England - Biochemistry, 1984-1990 (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - Benham, Graham Harvey - 1938 - England - Biochemistry, 1938-1987 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Bentley, John Phillip - 1947 - England - Vascular Surgery, 1947-1982 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Bentley, Ronald - 1946 - England - Chemistry, 1946-1975 (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - Bergfald, Odd Martin - 1955 - Norway - Criminology and Politics, 1955-1975 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Berlan, Jean Pierre - 1970 - France - Agricultural Economics, 1969-1975 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - Bernal, Martin Gardiner - 1962 - England - Chinese History, 1962-1980 (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - Besana, Mario - 1959 - Italy - Political Science, 1958-1976 (Box 15, Folder 131)
  - Betts, Alan Osbourne - 1955 - England - Veterinary Medicine, 1954-1990 (Box 16, Folder 132)
  - Beveridge, Gordon Smith Grieve - 1960 - Scotland - Chemical Engineering, 1959-1990 (Box 16, Folder 133)
  - Beveridge, William Ian Beardmore - 1937 - Australia - Veterinary Medicine, 1937-1986 (Box 16, Folder 134)
  - Biggart, John Henry - 1931 - Ireland - Medical and Biomedical Science, 1931-1980 (Box 16, Folder 135)
  - Biggs, John Michael - 1956 - England - Law, 1955-1975 (Box 16, Folder 136)
  - Bingham, Eardley Max - 1963 - Australia - Criminal Justice, 1962-1985 (Box 16, Folder 137)
  - Binns, Kenneth Johnstone - 1950 - Australia - Public Administration, 1948-1975 (Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Birch, Anthony Harold - 1951 - England - Political Science, 1946-1988 (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - Birch, Bryan John - 1957 - England - Mathematics, 1956-1985 (Box 17, Folder 140)
  - Bird, Terence Frederick - 1947 - England - Public Administration, 1947-1979 (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - Birtwhistle, Harrison - 1966 - England - Musical Composition, 1965-1990 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Bishop, Richard Evelyn Donohue - 1950 - England - Engineering, 1949-1987 (Box 17, Folder 143)
  - Black, Alison Harley - 1970 - Scotland - Chinese Philosophy, 1969-1985 (Box 17, Folder 144)
  - Black, Ian William Macleod - 1926 - Scotland - Spectrography, 1926-1963 (Box 17, Folder 145)
  - Black, Mary Ethna - 1989 - England - Public Health, 1988-1991 (Box 17, Folder 146)
  - Black, Maurice - 1927 - England - Geography, 1927-1974 (Box 17, Folder 147)
  - Blackburn, John Pointon - 1966 - England - Biomedical Engineering, 1966-1987 (Box 18, Folder 148)
  - Blackie, William John - 1937 - England - Biochemistry, 1936-1986 (Box 18, Folder 149)